Karnav Pargi

Software Engineer

Address Ahmedabad, 382470 Phone +91 878 049 8282 E-mail karnav.pargi@gmail.com **LinkedIn/Github/codewars** karnavpargi

Multitalented Software Engineer with experience of more than 5+ years in Web and Application software industry. Demonstrated excellent skills in **NodeJS**, **Angular**, JavaScript, and TypeScript. Novice in **React.js** True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy.

Technical Profile

Backend:-

- NodeJS, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, Nest.js, Strapi.io, Socket.io, Websocket. Passport.js, JWT Frontend:-
 - Angular 9+, React.is, Bootstrap, HTML, Next.is

CI-CD / DevOps:-

• Git, EC2, S3, SNS, SES, NginX, PM2, Jenkins, GitLab, Docker, Kubernetes

Work History

OCT 2021

- Current

Senior Software Engineer

Bytes Technolab Pvt. Ltd, Ahmedabad

- Led team of 3 members while providing exceptional customer service
- Trained and mentored junior developers and engineers, teaching skills in JavaScript, NodeJS, and working to improve overall team performance
- Demonstrated experience and good hands-on programming experience in NodeJS, Angular, and Reat.is.
- Integrated third-party tools and components into applications
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality
- Developed robust, scalable, modular, and API-centric infrastructures

SEP 2019 -OCT 2021

Software Developer

Digicorp Information Sys. Pvt. Ltd, Ahmedabad

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitiously, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality
- Developed robust, scalable, modular, and API-centric infrastructures
- Coordinated with project management on database development timelines
- Designed reusable and reliable code for use within distributed cloud environments

JAN 2018 -AUG 2019

IndiaNIC Infotech Ltd. Ahmedabad

- Worked as a dedicated entity.
- Communicate with clients for gathering feature requests, analyzing, and developing.
- Integrated third-party APIs from external applications into web platforms
- Developed server-side logic in NodeJS.
- Configured servers and managed provisioning
- Built APIs and data clients to consume APIs
- Managed efficient MongoDB queries and data transport

JUN 2017 -DEC 2017

JavaScript Developer

Lithe Technologies, Ahmedabad

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages
- Implemented changes and integrated requested elements to streamline business operations
- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues

Projects

FEB 2022 Current

Ragnar | Bytes technolab

Online events & races management systems.

- Manages the project with 3 developers.
- Communicate with client regarding the features, updates and feedback
- Implemented in the dashboard 2.0
- help to upgrade the angular v8 to v14

NOV 2021 JAN 2022

CPMS(OCPP) | Bytes technolab

Central system for vehicle charging station.

- Worked as a dedicated entity
- Successfully completed the phase one in NodeJS and React.is.
- Does the RnD for OCPP alliance and API's
- Implemented core system for connecting with the charging stations with help of websockets
- Communicate with client regarding the features, updates and feedback
- Implemented DB Designs for charging stations.
- Implemented the Security for connect with the charging stations(SSL).

FEB 2020 OCT 2021

JetPackED | Digicorp

SaaS based Data analysis tool.

- Implemented Multi layered Filter feature single handedly.(single, multi, checkbox) in Angular with Propeller UI
- Implemented API's for Schools, Classes, Teachers, etc data process and projected in III
- Implemented Datatables and wrote the algorithms for get the average percentages earned by the students.
- Part of the DB Desins for SaaS based architecture and microservices.
- Worked with Raw data's availed from the clever.com and separated to the different tables.
- Wrote the queries for the different modules in SQL.

SEP 2019 JAN 2020

Redprint & Revivn | Digicorp

Cloud-based asset management tool.

- Wrote the gueries for the different modules in SQL.
- Implemented forms and data tables in React.js
- implemented the logics for retrieve and stores the data with help of Redux store and axios.

JUN 2019 AUG 2019

Loveternational | IndiaNIC

Dating app.

- Designed Database, API's and wrote the mongoDB queries.
- Wrote the API's for Whole apps with help of NodeJS, ExpressJS, mongoose
- Implemented Chat App with help of Socket.io
- Impemented Payment gateways and wrote the algorithm to retrieve failed payments.
- Communicate with client regarding the features, updates and feedback

AUG 2018 MAY 2019

CPMS (Comp. Predictive management Sys.) | IndiaNIC

Yacht predictive parts service maintenance portal (offline).

- Implemented the algorithms with help of system design created by client for automatic service and part replacement.
- Communicate with client regarding the features, updates and feedback.
- Wrote the API's for Whole apps with help of NodeJS, ExpressJS, mongoose
- Wrote Scripts for automatic backup every day at mensioed time.

APR 2018 JUL 2018

Cancer Journey care | IndiaNIC

Cancer Diagnostics by predictive cancer-related questions.

- Designed Database, API's and wrote the mongoDB queries.
- Wrote the API's for Whole apps with help of NodeJS, ExpressJS, mongoose
- Implemented Conditional questions algorithm to provide questions based on answers selected by patient.
- Implemented payment service for questions asked by patients.

JAN 2018 MAR 2018

Tropitoken ICO | IndiaNIC

Buy TPN Cryptocurrency with any Crypto or cash.

- Designed Database, API's and wrote the mongoDB queries.
- Wrote the API's for Whole apps with help of NodeJS, ExpressJS, mongoose
- Implemented Coinpayments Payment service in which User pay in cash and get the TPN tokens.

JUN 2017 DEC 2017

EPOS Billing System | Lithe Technologies

Restaurant Billing systems.

- Wrote HTML/CSS for billing system
- wrote algorithms to create and calculate orders with help of JavaScript and Loki.js
- Wrote algorithms to calculate GST on Products.

Education

2010 2016	Bachelor of Engineering: InformationTechnology Gujarat Technological University - Gandhinagar, India
2007 2010	Diploma in Engineering: Information Technology RCTI Ahmedabad - Ahmedabad, India
2005 2007	Science in Mathematics R & L Pandya Hightschool, Dahod, Gujarat, India

Certifications

M001: MongoDB Basics. Cutshort Certified NodeJS.

Cutshort Certified Angular (2+)

Cutshort Certified Javascript

<u>More</u>